<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on The poetry of (in)security</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on The poetry of (in)security</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:10:52 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the eques elf smart plug: Part four</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-27-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:10:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-27-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-four/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part three, we finally figured out how to remotely control the smart power plugs (turn them on or off). In this final part, we are going to see how inadequate security controls can be exploited for various purposes. We are also going to look at one more scenario where the smart power plugs have no internet access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the eques elf smart plug: Part three</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-26-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 15:53:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-26-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part two, we figured out how to discover the smart plugs in a network and their details. We were also able to send remote commands to ikonkek2.com and query details about specific smart plugs. This was made possible by the discovery of a hardcoded aes key used to encrypt messages. We however still cannot turn a smart plug on or off remotely. So let&amp;rsquo;s concentrate on that in this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the eques elf smart plug: Part two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-25-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 14:23:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-25-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part one, we concentrated on analysing the network communication when one turns the smart power plug on or off from the app.&#xA;We had noticed some form of encrypted/encoded communication happening on udp port 27431 between the smart plug and the app installed on the phone. We also noticed some form of encrypted/encoded communication on tcp ports 9123 and 5222(xmpp) between the app, smart plug and ikonkek2.com.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting the eques elf smart plug: Part one</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-19-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 11:57:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-08-19-exploiting-the-eques-elf-smart-plug-part-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought some smart power plugs and they were pretty awesome! These are the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eques Elf smart plugs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; They can be controlled using an app through a connected Wi-Fi network, and remotely over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything was going on well till I noticed some strange urls on my home network monitoring system. It turns out it was the smart plug constantly communicating with some external hosts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard VPN: Portable Raspberry Pi Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-12-28-wireguard-vpn-portable-raspberry-pi-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 16:44:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-12-28-wireguard-vpn-portable-raspberry-pi-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We often use wireless networks to access the internet. This may be at home, work or even places like restaurants. When we connect to these networks, the security of our internet traffic is under the control of the owner of the wireless network. This is also the case when we connect to a wired connection on a network we don&amp;rsquo;t control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard VPN: Chained Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-12-28-wireguard-vpn-chained-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 07:33:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-12-28-wireguard-vpn-chained-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moving on from my previous &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;post&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; about setting up a typical Wireguard VPN connection, let&amp;rsquo;s go through how to do a chained setup. I will show how to do both the typical chained Wireguard VPN connection and the one with selective routing as described in my earlier post &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard VPN: Typical Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-11-14-wireguard-vpn-typical-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 07:51:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-11-14-wireguard-vpn-typical-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered the awesome &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wireguard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; VPN tunnel and I was sold. Wireguard is a simple, kernel-based, state-of-the-art VPN that also happens to be ridiculously fast and uses modern cryptographic principles that all other highspeed VPN solutions lack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VPNs! An OPSEC Primer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-11-12-vpns-an-opsec-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 12:05:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-11-12-vpns-an-opsec-primer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is a glorious place. This gloriousness does often come with some pitfalls here and there. Being probably the greatest source of information ever, various actors are constantly devicing ways to acquire and make use of all this data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2017 AfricaHackon Conference Badge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-06-28-the-2017-africahackon-conference-badge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 18:30:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-06-28-the-2017-africahackon-conference-badge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Information security conference badges have rapidly evolved over time. They have become a favorite among conference organisers and attendees as fun accessories that tie in to the conference experience. Unique badges have become collectible items that attendees keep and identify with a particular conference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Receiving Outernet Satellite Broadcasts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-12-29-receiving-outernet-satellite-broadcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 10:18:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-12-29-receiving-outernet-satellite-broadcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Receiving satellite data is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been hoping to try out for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s an area that captures the magic of long range radio communication and has become easier to experiment in as time has gone by.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hijacking wireless mice and keyboards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-07-09-hijacking-wireless-mice-and-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 14:40:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-07-09-hijacking-wireless-mice-and-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year researchers from &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bastille&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; discovered vulnerabilities in wireless mice and keyboards that could lead to them being remotely hijacked from as far as 225 meters away. They have a dedicated site detailing the vulnerabilities dubbed &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mousejack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. They also released POC code which I have built on to implement a remote takeover of a machine using a wireless mouse/keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DIY Listening Device</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-02-13-a-diy-listening-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 19:51:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-02-13-a-diy-listening-device/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a set of Intex Wireless Roaming Headphones lying around the house for a couple of years. They consist of a receiver (headphones) and a separate transmitter. The headphones include an FM receiver powered by two AAA batteries with reset and scan buttons for normal FM operation, and of course volume control. The separate transmitter comes with audio and microphone jack ports and is also powered by two AAA batteries. It also has a DC port as an alternative power source option. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it looks:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GSM: Sniffing voice traffic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-01-17-gsm-sniffing-voice-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 06:51:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-01-17-gsm-sniffing-voice-traffic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrap up the GSM series with a walkthrough on how to decrypt voice traffic. Voice is the way most people interact on a telecommunications network and therefore a major componenent of GSM traffic. I&amp;rsquo;ve explained a lot of the background on GSM communication in the previous posts so I&amp;rsquo;ll get right to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GSM: Sniffing SMS traffic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-11-29-gsm-sniffing-sms-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 10:14:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-11-29-gsm-sniffing-sms-traffic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;post&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, I explained how GSM traffic can be sniffed with the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HackRF One&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. GSM traffic carries a lot of information, from system information to the actual voice and data we are familiar with. The traffic that the normal user of a telecommunication network is concerned with is voice and data. With this in mind I&amp;rsquo;ll do a two part series to demonstrate how voice and data can be sniffed using the HackRF. I start with SMS traffic which falls under the data category. Let&amp;rsquo;s get right into it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sniffing GSM Traffic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-11-01-sniffing-gsm-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 09:30:27 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-11-01-sniffing-gsm-traffic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been playing around with the HackRF for the past couple of weeks and progressively exploring the Radio Frequency spectrum. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll take you through how to sniff GSM traffic. I&amp;rsquo;ll be specifically monitoring the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Um interface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. This in the air interface between the Mobile Station (MS) and the Base Transceiver Station (BTS). The MS in this case will be the mobile phone while the BTS is what the phone connects to on the Mobile network. The BTS is usually hosted on towers which you can spot in various locations. Here is what a typical one looks like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian ~ 127.0.0.1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-10-17-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 11:40:08 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-10-17-christian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#who are you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a passionate Information Security enthusiast. I specialize in Digital Forensics and Incident Response (DFIR). Research and artifacts analysis are the cause of my sleepless nights. I have a keen interest in PC and mobile device malware, I am therefore always tinkering with VMs and mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The HackRF One: First steps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-10-11-the-hackrf-one-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 20:18:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-10-11-the-hackrf-one-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wireless world is an area I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in for a long time. From the the more common applications such as Wi-Fi, bluetooth and FM to the lesser explored such as radar, satellite and GSM, radio frequency is an area I plan to explore extensively. How awesome is the concept of &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;electromagnetic pulses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in this age that is driven by electromagnetism. I digress so let me get back on track, there will be several more posts to explore the possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saints and Outlaws</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-10-04-saints-and-outlaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 09:06:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-10-04-saints-and-outlaws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been teaching a class on Network Security at mlab and one student asked what the state of cyber-security in the country was. In this post I explain the current state and the outlook over the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The BRO Chronicles 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-09-17-the-bro-chronicles-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 20:54:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-09-17-the-bro-chronicles-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part one I analysed the data communication that takes place on a phone over a one hour period. Read the post &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; for details and background info.&#xA;Here, I go further and analyse what happens over a twelve hour period of normal phone usage. I ran &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BRO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; on my phone from &lt;code&gt;6:40am&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;6:40pm&lt;/code&gt; and ensured that data was on and WIFI off the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers Wanted!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-09-13-hackers-wanted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 11:31:27 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-09-13-hackers-wanted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;####&amp;gt;Some expletives have been edited out&amp;lt;&#xA;####&amp;gt;The catching of feelings is encouraged&amp;lt;&#xA;####&amp;gt;Heavy Hip Hop references included&amp;lt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;####&amp;gt;Begin Rant&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The BRO Chronicles 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-09-06-the-bro-chronicles-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 08:56:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-09-06-the-bro-chronicles-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was having a random conversation with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. The conversation was based around Kali Nethunter and all the cool stuff that can be done with it. The discussion was revolving around &amp;ldquo;man in the middle attacks&amp;rdquo; and I suggested that having &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BRO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; running on Nethunter would be awesome. This got him excited and true to his nature, he couldn&amp;rsquo;t rest till he&amp;rsquo;d attempted it. Long story short, he did some amazing work and had it running soon afterwards complete with a detailed &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; guide. Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;strong&gt;guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to hack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-08-25-learning-to-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 14:27:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-08-25-learning-to-hack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Becoming a skilled hacker or the politically correct &amp;ldquo;information security specialist&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a straightforward defined path. Here I will try to layout what constitutes a good way to go about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AfricaHackon - Be part of the story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-05-17-africahackon-be-part-of-the-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 08:42:08 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-05-17-africahackon-be-part-of-the-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first heard of AfricaHackon at my previous job where I was working in IT. A colleague and friend told me about a conference about information security that would be held at our building. This was early last year. Being in charge of the network, I would be assisting in setting up internet access for the conference. Now when you&amp;rsquo;re incharge of the network and you hear you&amp;rsquo;ll be giving access to your network to a room full of the best &amp;ldquo;hackers&amp;rdquo; in the country, you get a bit nervous. I use the word &amp;ldquo;hackers&amp;rdquo; in quotes because that&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;d like to start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crypto magic - homomorphic encryption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-05-11-crypto-magic-homomorphic-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 13:45:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-05-11-crypto-magic-homomorphic-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Could Google do your search without knowing what it was looking for? Could your hospital provide you with information regarding your health records without knowing what you asked?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crypto magic - zero knowledge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-05-05-crypto-magic-zero-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 09:23:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-05-05-crypto-magic-zero-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some applications of cryptography that can only be classified as magical. It is only fitting that my first crypto post begins with one of them - zero knowledge proofs.&#xA;I will try and explain it without all the rather complicated mathematical stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bright</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-04-27-bright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 08:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-04-27-bright/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#who are you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bright Gameli Mawudor is my name. Friends in the infosec world call me ~ze3D~. A passionate information security engineer with a love for system exploitation, gleaning information from all corners of the web about a target, and social engineering using all possible methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-04-20-jade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 06:34:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-04-20-jade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#who are you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am Jade Solomon, an Infosec/Code machine, I dedicate a lot of sleepless nights to Reverse Engineering, GSM/Mobile technology and Exploit Development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-03-14-ck-the-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 19:46:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2015-03-14-ck-the-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#who are you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am an information security engineer with main interests in network security, hardware and radio frequency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
